Guide to the Stage Lighting Catalogs
Yale University Arts Library
Stage Lighting Catalogs
1880-1970
DRA 2
Yale University Arts Library
2.75
(3 boxes)
The collection consists of stage lighting company catalogs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of stage lighting company catalogs that document developments in stage lighting equipment from the early 1920s through 1970. Represented in the collection are manufacturers from the United States and Great Britain, including Century Lighting, Kliegl Brothers, Strand Electric & Engineering Co. Ltd., and Ward Leonard Electric Co. The collection also includes a selected lighting bibliography from circa 1880-1940.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Series I. Stage Lighting Catalogs. Series II. Selected Lighting Bibliography.
Stage lighting -- Catalogs; Stage lighting -- Bibliography; Century Lighting, Inc; Kliegl Bros. Universal Electric Stage Lighting Co; Strand Electric and Engineering Co. (London, England); Ward Leonard Electric Company, Mount Vernon, N.Y
- Stage Lighting Catalogs, Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by name of manufacturer, then by year of publication.
  - Ariel Davis Manufacturing Company, 1950-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ariel Davis Manufacturing Company, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Associated Lighting Service, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Belson Manufacturing Company, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Berkey-Colotran Incorporated, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Capitol Stage Lighting Company Incorporated, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Capron Lighting Incorporated, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Century Lighting Equipment Incorporated, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Century Lighting Equipment Incorporated, 1949-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Century Lighting Equipment Incorporated, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Display Lighting Company Incorporated, 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Electric, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Electric, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hub Electric Company, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kliegl Brothers, 1926-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kliegl Brothers, 1952-1961 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Kliegl Brothers, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lighting and Electronics Incorporated, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Metropolitan Electric Manufacturing Company, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mole-Richardson Company, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Northwestern Costume House Incorporated, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Scope and Contents
    Also includes: Strand Electric and Engineering Company
  - Olesen Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Siemens- Schuckertwerke Aktiengesellschaft, [1960?] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Strand Electric and Engineering Company, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Superior Electric Company, 1949-1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Superior Electric Company, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Theatre Production Service, 1951,1958 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Theatre Technology Incorporated, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Trumbull Electric Manufacturing Company, [193-] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Vickers Incorporated, Division of Sperry Rand Corporation, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ward Leonard Electric Company, 1924-1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ward Leonard Electric Company, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Ward Leonard Electric Company, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Wenger Corporation, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Selected Lighting Bibliography, Series II
  - Selected Lighting Bibliography, circa 1880-1940 (Box 3)
    The Selected Lighting Bibliography is a card catalog with entries for publications concerning various aspects of lighting. The card catalog is arranged alphabetically by subject.